Dennis Kamau



dmkamau475@gmail.com



linkedin.com/in/denmau



254759360020



https://denmau.me

Summary

I am a Software Engineer with frontend and backend skills. Today, I am focusing on delivering APIs that scale. I am TensorFlow-certified and I enjoy building and serving Machine Learning models with TensorFlow.

My skills span from software design, building mobile applications with Flutter and Java, Web applications with Vue.js, and the backend with Django or PHP. I have experience with containers (Docker), API integrations, and PowerBi.

Experience



.NET Developer

The Jitu.com

Nov 2021 - Present (1 month +)

Software Engineer

Startappz Limited

Oct 2021 - Nov 2021 (2 months)

- Deployed and Managed Linux servers on 'the cloud'.
- Developed and Maintained Deployment pipelines for various projects.
- Built and Architected consumer-facing Web and Mobile Applications.
- Built RESTful APIs with PHP and integrated them with Flutter mobile Applications.

Junior Machine Learning Engineer

Omdena

May 2021 - Nov 2021 (7 months)

- Reduced business expenses immensely by implementing computer vision with OpenCV.
- Built and optimized Machine Learning models with TensorFlow.
- Conceptualized APIs to serve ML models to edge devices.
- Collaborated with an agile remote team on Slack, with weekly meetings with the business owner.

Junior Web Developer (PHP and Flutter)

Startappz Limited

Jul 2021 - Sep 2021 (3 months)

- Developed bespoke Web applications with PHP, JavaScript, Ajax, and HTML/CSS.
- Developed Mobile applications with Flutter, often while collaborating with a UI/UX Designer.
- Developed beautiful UI for internal tools and automated backend tasks.
- · API integrations and Database management.
- Helped with System Design.

zuri. Backend Developer Intern

Zuri Team, Inc.

Mar 2021 - Jun 2021 (4 months)

- Work on Full-Stack web projects with Python Django.
- Collaborate with other interns on projects over slack as a Backend Developer.
- Worked on a site that links drivers to a mechanic from any part of Nigeria!
- · Used tools such as Python, Django, and SQL.

Frontend Developer, BuildForSDG Challenge 2020

Andela

Jul 2020 - Nov 2020 (5 months)

- Collaborated in an agile remote team to innovate on real-world, locally and relevant solutions focused on the Sustainable Development Goals(SDGs).
- worked on a team project to connect farmers to consumers.
- · Prepared visual presentations for team meetings.
- Used HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap and jQuery.

Education



Bachelor's degree, Computer Science 2019 - May 2021

eMobilis Mobile Technology Institute

Full Stack Software Development

2021 - 2021

- PHP | JavaScript | HTML / CSS | MySQL
- Java Android Development
- · API Integrations and Firebase

Apps:Lab

21C Skills Training, Software Engineering

Oct 2020 - Feb 2021

- Strong Computer Science principles and Data Structures & Algorithms.
- Learned the importance of Testing and how to go about it, and test automation.

Licenses & Certifications

DeepLearning.Al TensorFlow Developer Specialization - DeepLearning.Al

TensorFlow Developer Certificate - TensorFlow Certificate Program